<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>tedmehl.me</title>
  <subtitle>Playground of half-baked ideas.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://tedmehl.me/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://tedmehl.me/" />
  <updated>2025-10-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>https://tedmehl.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Ted</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>The internet used to be a place</title>
    <link href="https://tedmehl.me/notes/the-internet-used-to-be-a-place/" />
    <updated>2025-10-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://tedmehl.me/notes/the-internet-used-to-be-a-place/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The internet used to be a place. A place you would visit. We had rooms or corners dedicated to them. When you left those spaces, you left the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to wonder what it would be like if we treated the internet like that again.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Are you still checking this? </title>
    <link href="https://tedmehl.me/notes/are-you-still-checking-this/" />
    <updated>2025-09-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://tedmehl.me/notes/are-you-still-checking-this/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just making sure the one person that checks this website is paying attention. I have a CMS set up now.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>When one door closes, another door opens.</title>
    <link href="https://tedmehl.me/notes/when-one-door-closes/" />
    <updated>2025-07-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://tedmehl.me/notes/when-one-door-closes/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So the saying goes. My personal experience has been a little different, however. Sometimes I see a closed door and assume it&#39;s locked, but I haven&#39;t even bothered to try the handle.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Create More, Consume Less</title>
    <link href="https://tedmehl.me/blog/create-more-consume-less/" />
    <updated>2025-06-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://tedmehl.me/blog/create-more-consume-less/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week, I was browsing YouTube and came across a video about a habit that will change your life. Being a sucker for seeing what other people deem life-changing, I watched the video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you search the internet for resources on habits, you&#39;ll notice there are countless articles and videos touting the virtues of habits followed by highly successful people. Millionaires, CEOs, actors and actresses, other people deemed important. People whose lifestyles, circumstances, and personalities likely don&#39;t match your own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This video was not one of those. Its premise was simple: &lt;strong&gt;When you have the urge to consume, try to create instead.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, obviously they don&#39;t mean in all circumstances. There are plenty of things, such as consuming food and water, that you simply can&#39;t avoid. But what about the other kinds of consumption?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We live in a world where everything is heavily marketed and packaged for our easy digestion. Algorithmic feeds trying to figure out what content will get us to use their services &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; a bit longer. Everything ultra-processed into what author Cal Newport refers to as &lt;a href=&quot;https://calnewport.com/on-ultra-processed-content/&quot;&gt;digital Doritos&lt;/a&gt;. Technically harmless ingredients, broken down to their base forms, and then put back together into something irresistible. Like that bag of Doritos you know you shouldn&#39;t eat in one sitting but do anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would rather not spend all my free time for the rest of my life consuming bags of digital Doritos. Given the choice between being a consumer and a creator, I&#39;d rather be a creator, and I hope you would too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if creation is key to reducing this kind of consumption, what does that look like? What would it mean for me to create instead of mindlessly consume? How do I curate a life where creating is the default? What defines creating? Those are great questions, and I don&#39;t have the answers. Not yet anyway. For now, the important thing is that I&#39;m thinking about it, and I&#39;m looking forward to seeing what I come up with.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Things That Ground Us</title>
    <link href="https://tedmehl.me/blog/the-things-that-ground-us/" />
    <updated>2024-12-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://tedmehl.me/blog/the-things-that-ground-us/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We get older and technology gets smarter, more integrated into everyday life. And yet, I find myself reaching for the things of the so-called past. Things often considered outdated, antiquated, and a waste of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Handwriting or cursive? Why teach what nobody uses anymore? Who writes handwritten letters? Why shoot film or own a camera when your phone has one already? Why wear a watch when your phone tells the time? Why listen to vinyl records when Spotify and YouTube exist?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies combine technology and the internet into many things. Because of this, it can often feel like we lose connections to things in the physical world. Things we hold. Things we help create. Things with a craftsmanship that gives us wonder. Things that help us feel more connected by allowing us to disconnect. Things that keep us in the present or bring back precious memories of the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of these technological improvements seem focused on our need for immediacy. Getting us what we want as fast as possible. In doing so, they focus on the outcome, the destination, and not the journey. It&#39;s in the journey where life happens. Where failure happens. Where joy and hurt, love and loss happen. It builds us up and shapes us. The things we take with us are an integral part of that journey, and how we use them matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re not Luddites. We don&#39;t reject technology. Instead, we seek to be more intentional about its role in our lives. We don&#39;t want to lose sight of the things and people in front of us that keep us grounded.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>To Live Deliberately</title>
    <link href="https://tedmehl.me/blog/to-live-deliberately/" />
    <updated>2024-11-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://tedmehl.me/blog/to-live-deliberately/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to the woods because I wished to live deliberately, to front only the essential facts of life and see if I could not learn what it had to teach, and not, when I came to die, discover I had not lived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Henry David Thoreau&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be too easy at times to binge-watch YouTube videos. They have the algorithm down, recommending interesting thing after interesting thing. Other times it’s a TV show, and the episodes are short. What&#39;s the harm in watching one more (and another, and another)? When I finally peel myself away from the screen, I&#39;m often left feeling empty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people don’t have the luxury or interest in doing what Thoreau did—finding a cabin by a pond to live in for a time. His words, however, make me think about how I live my life. I don’t want to look back years later and wonder what I could have done with all that wasted time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I, too, seek to live deliberately. But, I suspect I will spend my entire life working out how, and that&#39;s ok.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Not all who wander are lost...</title>
    <link href="https://tedmehl.me/notes/not-all-who-wander-are-lost/" />
    <updated>2024-09-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://tedmehl.me/notes/not-all-who-wander-are-lost/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;But just because you are wandering doesn&#39;t mean you aren&#39;t lost.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>If we were in a zombie apocalypse, what skills would you bring?</title>
    <link href="https://tedmehl.me/notes/zombie-apocolypse/" />
    <updated>2024-09-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://tedmehl.me/notes/zombie-apocolypse/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A coworker posed this question recently. Some had outdoorsman skills or other relevant knowledge. I mean, I could probably make a website, but I&#39;m still trying to figure out how that adds to the group.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Good Enough</title>
    <link href="https://tedmehl.me/blog/good-enough/" />
    <updated>2024-01-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://tedmehl.me/blog/good-enough/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;To me, perfectionism is this unrelenting desire to do something right the first time that overwhelms and prevents me from attempting it in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s obsessing over details that don&#39;t matter to anyone else but me. Needing the &amp;quot;perfect&amp;quot; tool for the job and not using what I already have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s expecting the same results as someone with years of experience when I don&#39;t have any. Setting standards so high I know I won&#39;t be able to reach them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s fearing failure at a high level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, it might help me do certain things with a level of exactitude others might not bother with. A large part of the time it&#39;s a pain in my side, preventing me from doing things I actually want to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What can perfectionism look like?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m a hobbyist bookbinder. I like to create tangible things with my hands. This pairs well with my love of good stationery and writing implements. It&#39;s also an outlet that lets me disconnect from my job that involves staring at screens 8 hours a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first got started in the hobby, I did lots of research. I found some tutorials and bought all the tools and materials I needed to create my first book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took me a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;whole year&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; from the time I got all my materials before I finally made that book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had an image in my head of what I wanted and how it would go that was not realistic. I wanted the pages to be even, the corners lined up perfectly, the sewing to be exact, and on and on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m well aware that to become better at something you need to practice doing that something. Staring at my pile of materials wasn&#39;t going to get me anywhere if I didn&#39;t actually attempt to make the thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I finally had enough of putting it off and made my first book, the result was…good enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made mistakes and had many areas of improvement, but it was good enough. That&#39;s all it needed to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perfect meant I would never get it done. Good enough meant I had an actual book in my hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&#39;s good enough?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a perfectionist, it&#39;s hard to be ok with good enough. But for me, it has been one of the most important things to come to grips with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good enough might mean I stop worrying about the tiny details of a photo. I&#39;m posting it to Instagram and nobody is going to notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might mean I don&#39;t need bookbinding-specific needles yet. Yarn darner needles from Walmart will get the job done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might mean the return on investment to go that last 10% and make it perfect isn&#39;t worth the effort required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn&#39;t mean I stop being a perfectionist. That&#39;s part of who I am and isn&#39;t going away. I will still fuss over the details of whatever I&#39;m doing, but I am going to make mistakes and that&#39;s ok. I will take those mistakes and use them to improve the next time. Slowly but surely getting better through every good enough thing I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does good enough mean for you?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I only work when inspiration strikes</title>
    <link href="https://tedmehl.me/notes/inspiration/" />
    <updated>2023-12-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://tedmehl.me/notes/inspiration/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fortunately it strikes at nine every morning.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>