<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>tedmehl.me</title>
  <subtitle>Playground of half-baked ideas.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://tedmehl.me/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://tedmehl.me/" />
  <updated>2024-12-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>https://tedmehl.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Ted</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>The Things That Ground Us</title>
    <link href="https://tedmehl.me/blog/the-things-that-ground-us/" />
    <updated>2024-12-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://tedmehl.me/blog/the-things-that-ground-us/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We get older and technology gets smarter, more integrated into everyday life. And yet, I find myself reaching for the things of the so-called past. Things often considered outdated, antiquated, and a waste of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Handwriting or cursive? Why teach what nobody uses anymore? Who writes handwritten letters? Why shoot film or own a camera when your phone has one already? Why wear a watch when your phone tells the time? Why listen to vinyl records when Spotify and YouTube exist?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies combine technology and the internet into many things. Because of this, it can often feel like we lose connections to things in the physical world. Things we hold. Things we help create. Things with a craftsmanship that gives us wonder. Things that help us feel more connected by allowing us to disconnect. Things that keep us in the present or bring back precious memories of the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of these technological improvements seem focused on our need for immediacy. Getting us what we want as fast as possible. In doing so, they focus on the outcome, the destination, and not the journey. It&#39;s in the journey where life happens. Where failure happens. Where joy and hurt, love and loss happen. It builds us up and shapes us. The things we take with us are an integral part of that journey, and how we use them matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re not Luddites. We don&#39;t reject technology. Instead, we seek to be more intentional about its role in our lives. We don&#39;t want to lose sight of the things and people in front of us that keep us grounded.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>To Live Deliberately</title>
    <link href="https://tedmehl.me/blog/to-live-deliberately/" />
    <updated>2024-11-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://tedmehl.me/blog/to-live-deliberately/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to the woods because I wished to live deliberately, to front only the essential facts of life and see if I could not learn what it had to teach, and not, when I came to die, discover I had not lived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Henry David Thoreau&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be too easy at times to binge-watch YouTube videos. They have the algorithm down, recommending interesting thing after interesting thing. Other times it’s a TV show, and the episodes are short. What&#39;s the harm in watching one more (and another, and another)? When I finally peel myself away from the screen, I&#39;m often left feeling empty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people don’t have the luxury or interest in doing what Thoreau did—finding a cabin by a pond to live in for a time. His words, however, make me think about how I live my life. I don’t want to look back years later and wonder what I could have done with all that wasted time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I, too, seek to live deliberately. But, I suspect I will spend my entire life working out how, and that&#39;s ok.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Good Enough</title>
    <link href="https://tedmehl.me/blog/good-enough/" />
    <updated>2024-01-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://tedmehl.me/blog/good-enough/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;To me, perfectionism is this unrelenting desire to do something right the first time that overwhelms and prevents me from attempting it in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s obsessing over details that don&#39;t matter to anyone else but me. Needing the &amp;quot;perfect&amp;quot; tool for the job and not using what I already have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s expecting the same results as someone with years of experience when I don&#39;t have any. Setting standards so high I know I won&#39;t be able to reach them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s fearing failure at a high level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, it might help me do certain things with a level of exactitude others might not bother with. A large part of the time it&#39;s a pain in my side, preventing me from doing things I actually want to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What can perfectionism look like?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m a hobbyist bookbinder. I like to create tangible things with my hands. This pairs well with my love of good stationery and writing implements. It&#39;s also an outlet that lets me disconnect from my job that involves staring at screens 8 hours a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first got started in the hobby, I did lots of research. I found some tutorials and bought all the tools and materials I needed to create my first book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took me a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;whole year&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; from the time I got all my materials before I finally made that book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had an image in my head of what I wanted and how it would go that was not realistic. I wanted the pages to be even, the corners lined up perfectly, the sewing to be exact, and on and on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m well aware that to become better at something you need to practice doing that something. Staring at my pile of materials wasn&#39;t going to get me anywhere if I didn&#39;t actually attempt to make the thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I finally had enough of putting it off and made my first book, the result was…good enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made mistakes and had many areas of improvement, but it was good enough. That&#39;s all it needed to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perfect meant I would never get it done. Good enough meant I had an actual book in my hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&#39;s good enough?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a perfectionist, it&#39;s hard to be ok with good enough. But for me, it has been one of the most important things to come to grips with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good enough might mean I stop worrying about the tiny details of a photo. I&#39;m posting it to Instagram and nobody is going to notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might mean I don&#39;t need bookbinding-specific needles yet. Yarn darner needles from Walmart will get the job done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might mean the return on investment to go that last 10% and make it perfect isn&#39;t worth the effort required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn&#39;t mean I stop being a perfectionist. That&#39;s part of who I am and isn&#39;t going away. I will still fuss over the details of whatever I&#39;m doing, but I am going to make mistakes and that&#39;s ok. I will take those mistakes and use them to improve the next time. Slowly but surely getting better through every good enough thing I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does good enough mean for you?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Everyone Starts Like Klinger</title>
    <link href="https://tedmehl.me/blog/klinger/" />
    <updated>2023-09-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://tedmehl.me/blog/klinger/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In an episode of M*A*S*H, Radar, a radio operator at a mobile hospital during the Korean War, finally gets to go home to the US. Klinger, his replacement, has a terrible time trying to learn his new job on the fly. Members of the camp spend much of the episode giving him a hard time for not being as quick on his feet as Radar. It&#39;s not until later that they cut him some slack. While Radar was good at his job then, they recognized that he also started like Klinger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always thought that was an important thing to remember. You may feel disheartened when you don&#39;t have the same skill level as someone who&#39;s been at it for years. You might be trying to fill the shoes of someone with decades of experience and don&#39;t know if you can. Whatever the circumstance, remember that at some point in their life, they, too, started like Klinger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone starts like Klinger.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Practical Superpowers: Line-of-sight Teleportation</title>
    <link href="https://tedmehl.me/blog/teleportation/" />
    <updated>2023-09-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://tedmehl.me/blog/teleportation/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Comic books and superhero movies have shown us much in the way of traditional superpowers like flight, super speed, and super strength. But what about superpowers with purposeful constraints? Powers that impart no meaningful value in and of themselves, or ones that do but with limits or side effects. Over the years, I have created a few of my own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One such power is line-of-sight teleportation. Unlike traditional teleportation, where you appear wherever you want, you must see in real life the place to which you are teleporting (no photographs). The end of the street. Your living room through the window of your house. The tree way off on the horizon. If you can see it, you can teleport there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, when walking, I will take a purposeful blink and imagine I&#39;ve moved to the end of the street. Or wonder how many jumps it would take to complete my work commute during the windy winter months. Or imagine teleporting down the highway on the way to see a friend, confusing drivers as I appear and disappear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Note: I am working on the assumption that things you are wearing or things you are holding come with you when you teleport. But don&#39;t think too hard about the actual logistics of the power. Imagine the idea at its simplest.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How would you use line-of-sight teleportation powers?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I like to complicate things.</title>
    <link href="https://tedmehl.me/blog/first-post/" />
    <updated>2023-08-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://tedmehl.me/blog/first-post/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It starts with an idea. One of those &amp;quot;wouldn&#39;t it be cool if I did...&amp;quot; Then I do some research about the thing (I generally enjoy researching things). Then over the next few days, as I learn more and add on to the idea, I turn something that was once simple into a complicated mess of a project. It no longer feels fun. It becomes a daunting chore full of unnecessary requirements I&#39;ve placed on myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;That&#39;s how this project started.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a few years now I&#39;ve wanted to start my own blog. A blog to house the random thoughts or ideas I had, but also a blog that would teach me a thing or two about static site generators (SSGs) and modern web development techniques along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn&#39;t until this summer that I finally got serious about the idea. I started planning a simple site that had a few basic requirements. I had my SSG picked out. I had some basic style ideas I would implement. Then I started doing some research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It went something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, I should get a headless content management system so I can have a cool authoring experience. Let me google the best ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well this one is rated well, but isn&#39;t free. This one is too complex. This one is too simple. The editing experience on this one doesn&#39;t look that great. If I decide to switch CMS&#39;s will all my content be stuck on that platform, or can I migrate?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do I even need a headless CMS?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I should make a mockup. I wonder what tools exist for making mockups? I&#39;ve heard figma is used a lot in the UI/UX design space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do they have a free option? Is it even the best tool out there anymore? It&#39;s kind of getting old. And Adobe tried to buy it but the deal hasn&#39;t gone through yet. What else is out there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Penpot is open source, but other people say it&#39;s missing some features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&#39;s the best way to organize my CSS stylesheets? What&#39;s standard practice? Let me watch some videos on this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so on...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Just like that...&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d spent weeks of my spare time researching content management systems, pretending I needed to learn a new design tool, spending hours on YouTube watching web development techniques, continuously adding complexity. Not all of what I learned was useless, but most of it wasn&#39;t contributing towards my goal. Instead it made me tired. It didn&#39;t sound fun anymore, but more like work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was eventually brought back to reality by a Kevin Powell video. To paraphrase: You can spend all this time watching YouTube videos, but at some point you have to start making something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Properly called out, I took a step back, simplified and refocused my efforts around the original intent, and got to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you see is the current result. But it&#39;s a living work in progress and will probably change over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway. Expect posts about anything and everything in sporadic intervals.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>